[柯克]舰长日志，星历5843.7
[Kirk] Captain's log, stardate 5843.7.
企业号正被肆虐的流行病阴影笼罩
The Enterprise is in the grip of a raging epidemic.
已有三名船员死亡
Three crewmen have died
23人因瑞吉利热倒下
and 23 have been struck down by Rigelian fever.
为了对抗疾病
In order to combat the illness,
麦考伊医生需要大量的瑞他啉
Dr. McCoy needs large quantities of ryetalyn,
是这种发热的唯一已知的退烧药
which is the only known antidote for the fever.
我们的传感器检测到了大量的纯瑞他啉
Our sensors have picked up sufficient quantities of pure ryetalyn
在欧米茄星系的一颗小行星上
on a small planet in the Omega system.
我们正传送下去，获取这种急需的材料
We are beaming down to secure this urgently needed material.
报告
Report.
吉姆，四公里外有一个大矿床，方位273
Jim, there's a large deposit, bearing 273, four kilometers away.
[麦考伊] 我有四个小时来处理它
[McCoy] I've got four hours to process that stuff.
否则疫情将不可逆转
Otherwise the epidemic will be irreversible.
企业号上的每个人将会…
Everybody on board the Enterprise will...
奇怪
Strange.
读数表明附近有人类生命形式
Readings indicate a life-form in the vicinity, apparently human.
然而，飞船传感器显示这颗行星无人居住
Yet ship sensors indicated this planet was uninhabited.
让我们去弄到那个瑞他啉
Let's get that ryetalyn.
[电子叮当声]
[Electronic Clanging]
没用
Inoperative.
不要杀人
Do not kill.
我是詹姆斯·柯克舰长
I'm Captain James Kirk...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我一直在监视你的飞船，自从它进入这个星系
I have monitored your ship since it entered this system.
那既然你知道我们是谁，你也知道我们为什么在这里，怎么称呼？
Then if you know who we are, you know why we're here, Mr...?
弗林特，你得离开我的星球
Flint. You will leave my planet.
你说是你的星球，先生？
Did you say your planet, sir?
我的隐居之地，逃避地球生活
My retreat from the unpleasantness of life on Earth
和人类陪伴的的不愉快
and the company of people.
弗林特先生，我的船员们病了
Mr. Flint, I have a sick crew up there.
我们无法及时到达另一个星球
We can't possibly reach another planet in time.
你不能拒绝给我们瑞他啉
You can't refuse us the ryetalyn.
你这是非法入侵，舰长
You're trespassing, Captain.
我们有需要
We're in need.
我们会支付费用的，工作也好，物品交换也行
We'll pay for it, work for it, trade for it.
你没有我想要的
You have nothing I want.
但你有我们需要的瑞他啉
But you have the ryetalyn that we need.
如果有必要，我们会采取强制手段
If necessary, we'll take it.
如果你不主动离开，我有能力强制让你走
If you do not leave voluntarily, I have the power to force you.
或者原地杀了你
Or kill you where you stand.
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[Kirk] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第十九集
Requiem for Methuselah
玛士撒拉的安魂曲
柯克呼叫企业号，斯科特先生，将相位炮瞄准我们的坐标
Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott, lock phasers onto our coordinates.
[斯科特] 是的，舰长，所有相位炮都已瞄准
[Scott] Aye, Captain. All phasers locked on.
弗林特先生，如果我们出了什么事
Mr. Flint, if anything happens to us,
你也别想逃，随后我的船员会下来拿瑞他啉
four deaths and then my crew comes down and takes that ryetalyn.
一个有趣的权力测试
An interesting test of power.
你我的巨大力量对抗，谁会赢？
Your enormous forces against mine. Who would win?
弗林特先生，除非你确定
Mr. Flint, unless you are certain,
否则我建议你不要做无用的实验
I would suggest you refrain from a most useless experiment.
我们只需要几个小时
We need only a few hours.
你见过里瑞吉利热的受害者吗？
Have you ever seen a victim of Rigelian fever?
他们在一天之内死去
They die in one day.
其效力就像黑死病一样
The effects are like Bubonic plague.
1334年，夏天，君士坦丁堡
Constantinople, summer, 1334.
它沿着街道，下水道散布开来
It marched through the streets, the sewers.
乘牛车，经水路离开城市，杀死了半个欧洲
It left the city by oxcart, by sea, to kill half of Europe.
老鼠们在夜里发出沙沙声和尖叫声，它们也死了
The rats, rustling and squealing in the night, as they, too, died.
老鼠…
The rats...
你是历史系的学者吗，先生？
Are you a student of history, sir?
是的
I am.
企业号，一艘瘟疫飞船
The Enterprise, a plague ship.
你有两个小时，两小时内你们得离开
You have two hours, at the end of which time, you will leave.
十分感激
With all due gratitude.
M-4会收集你需要的瑞他啉
M-4 will gather the ryetalyn which you need.
请允许我为你们提供更舒适的环境
Permit me to offer you more comfortable surroundings.
进来吧，长官们
Come in, gentlemen.
我们的飞船传感器没有显示你在这里，弗林特先生
Our ship's sensors did not reveal your presence here, Mr. Flint.
我的星球被屏幕环绕，创造毫无生气的印象
My planet is surrounded by screens which create the impression of lifelessness:
一种阻止好奇，不速之客的保护
A protection against the curious, the uninvited.
那你一个人住在这里
Then you live here alone.
除了M-4，它充当男仆、女仆、园丁和护卫
Except for M-4, which serves as butler, housekeeper, gardener and guardian.
令人印象深刻的家，弗林特先生
A most impressive home, Mr. Flint.
是的，莎士比亚第一对开本，古腾堡圣经
Yes. Shakespeare first folio, a Gutenberg Bible.
半人马座七号的塔拉努卢斯的创作版画
The Creation lithographs by Taranullus of Centauri Seven.
这是几个世纪以来银河系中最稀有的藏书之一
That's one of the rarest book collections in the galaxy, spanning centuries.
不要拘束，先生们
Be comfortable, gentlemen.
随便喝点白兰地
Help yourselves to brandy.
我们能信任他吗？
Do we trust him?
目前这样做似乎是合乎逻辑的
It would seem logical to do so for the moment.
嗯，我需要两个小时把瑞他啉处理成抗毒素
Well, I'll need two hours to process that ryetalyn into antitoxin.
如果一小时后瑞他啉还没有到
If that ryetalyn isn't here in one hour,
我们就去勘探，如果必要越过弗林特先生
we'll go prospecting, right over Mr. Flint if necessary.
这是我见过的最了不起的私人艺术收藏，也是最独特的
This is the most splendid private collection of art I've ever seen, and the most unique:
大部分是列奥纳多·达·芬奇的作品
the majority are the works of Leonardo da Vinci,
文艺复兴时期
Renaissance period.
雷金纳德·波拉克的部分作品，20世纪
some of the works of Reginald Pollack, 20th century,
甚至有一把来自马库斯二号的轻机关枪
and even a Sten from Marcus II.
我终于见到了其他人类
At last I've seen other humans.
其他男人
Other men.
有一个不是人类
One is not human.
瓦肯人
The Vulcan.
原来那就是瓦肯人
So that is a Vulcan.
我想和他讨论次维度物理
I'd like to discuss subdimensional physics with him.
你已经把该领域你所知道的一切都教给了我，你说瓦肯人知道的更多
You've taught me all you know in the area and you say Vulcanís know more.
即使他的智力既不如你，也不如我
Even he is not your intellectual equal, nor mine.
让我见见他们
Let me meet them.
他们自私、残暴，是人类群体的一部分
They are selfish, brutal, a part of the human community
我拒绝与之为伍，并把你隔绝开来
which I rejected and from which I've shielded you.
他们很快就会走的，让我见见他们
Soon they will be gone. Let me meet them.
蕾娜…
Rayna...
你孤独过吗？
Have you been lonely?
什么是孤独？
What is loneliness?
是一种渴望
It is a thirst.
是一朵凋谢在沙漠中的花
It is a flower dying in the desert.
弗林特，不要把这个机会从我身边夺走
Flint, don't take this opportunity away from me.
它是如此令人兴奋
It's so exciting.
令人兴奋？
Exciting?
你以前从来没有对我提出过要求
You have never made a demand of me before.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不要觉得抱歉
Do not be sorry.
可能会很有趣
It might be interesting.
蜥牌白兰地，百年陈酿，来点吗吉姆？
Saurian brandy, 100 years old. Jim?
当然
Please.
史波克先生，我知道你不会喝的
Mr. Spock, I know you won't have one.
天堂禁止那些数学上完美的脑电波
Heaven forbid those mathematically perfect brain waves
被这种过于人性化的恶习所腐蚀
be corrupted by this all too human vice.
谢谢，医生，我要一杯白兰地
Thank you, Doctor. I will have a brandy.
你觉得我们俩能应付一个喝醉的瓦肯人吗？
Do you think the two of us can handle a drunk Vulcan?
一旦酒精接触到绿色血液…
Once alcohol hits that green blood...
如果我显得心不在焉，那是因为我所看到的
If I appear distracted, it is because of what I've seen.
我快要体验到一种不寻常的情绪了
I am close to experiencing an unaccustomed emotion.
我要为此喝一杯
I'll drink to that.
什么情绪？
What emotion?
嫉妒
Envy.
这些达芬奇画作都没有被编目或复制过
None of these da Vinci paintings has been cataloged or reproduced.
它们是不知名的作品
They are unknown works,
从最后一笔抑或是材料的使用都明显是真迹
all apparently authentic to the last brushstroke and use of materials.
未被发现的达芬奇本会是无价的
As undiscovered da Vinciís, they would be priceless.
本会是？你是说你认为它们是赝品？
Would be? You mean you think they're fakes?
真奇怪，一个像弗林特这样富有和无可挑剔的品味的人
Most strange. A man of Flint's obvious wealth and impeccable taste
几乎不需要挂赝品
scarcely needs to hang fakes.
然而我的三录仪分析表明，使用的画布和颜料
Yet my tricorder analysis indicates that the canvas and pigments used
产自当代
are of contemporary origin.
嗯，这可能就是它本来的样子
Well, this could be what it seems to be.
或者它可能是一个伪装，一个陷阱，甚至是一个幻觉
Or it could be a cover, a set up, or even an illusion.
这可以解释这些画，类似于真实的东西
That could explain the paintings, similar to the real thing.
史波克，尽早读取我们主人的完整三录仪数据，看看他是不是人类
Spock, at your earliest opportunity, take a full tricorder reading of our host. See if he's human.
柯克呼叫企业号，斯科特先生？
Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott?
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
斯科特先生，对弗林特先生进行全面电脑检查
Mr. Scott, run a full computer check on Mr. Flint
以及霍尔贝格917G这颗星球
and on this planet Holberg 917G.
准备好你的结果，我会联系你的
Stand by with your results. I'll contact.
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
让我们好好享用这杯白兰地，尝起来是真的
Let's enjoy this brandy. It tastes real.
小心
Easy.
老骨头？
Bones?
瑞他啉，准备处理为抗毒素
Ryetalyn, ready to be processed into antitoxin.
传送上船并开始处理
Beam up to the ship and start processing.
没必要，舰长
That will not be necessary, Captain.
在我的实验室，M-4可以比在船上更快地准备瑞他啉接种
M-4 can prepare the ryetalyn for inoculation more quickly in my laboratory than you could aboard your ship.
当然，我想对此进行监督
I would like to supervise that, of course.
当你对流程感到满意时，我希望你们能赏光和我一起吃晚餐
And when you are satisfied as to procedures, I hope you will do me the honour of being my guests at dinner.
谢谢，弗林特先生，我认为我们没有时间
Thank you, Mr. Flint. I don't think we have the time.
我后悔我早先的冷淡，让我来补偿一下
I regret my earlier inhospitality. Let me make amends.
先生们，请让我介绍一下蕾娜
Gentlemen, may I present Rayna.
我以为你一个人住
I thought you lived alone.
我的意思是除了我的家人没有其他人
I meant there are no others besides my family.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，我希望我们能找个时间讨论场密度
Mr. Spock, I do hope we can find a moment to discuss field density
以及它与重力现象的关系
and its relationship to gravity phenomena.
是吗，我会很喜欢这样的讨论
Indeed. I would appreciate such a talk.
这是我的兴趣所在
It is an interest of mine.
柯克舰长
Captain Kirk.
柯克舰长？
Captain Kirk?
蕾娜
Rayna.
她的父母在我受雇期间在一次事故中丧生
Her parents were killed in an accident while in my employ.
临死前，他们把孩子，也就是蕾娜·卡佩克，交给我看管
Before dying, they placed their infant, Rayna Kapec, in my custody.
我抚养并教育了她
I have raised and educated her.
令人印象深刻的成果，先生
With most impressive results, sir.
除了重力现象，你还有什么感兴趣的，蕾娜？
What else interests you besides gravity phenomena, Rayna?
所有东西，否则就是对智力的背叛
Everything. Less than that is betrayal of the intellect.
整个宇宙？所有的知识？
The totality of the universe? All knowledge?
蕾娜拥有 17 个大学科学和艺术学位
Rayna possesses 17 university degrees in the sciences and arts.
她知道智力并不是全部
She is aware that the intellect is not all.
但它的培养必须是第一位的，否则人就会出错
But its cultivation must come first, or the individual makes errors.
在无意义的追求上浪费时间
Wastes time in unprofitable pursuits.
我在她这个年纪的时候，相当喜欢犯无伤大雅的错误
At her age, I rather enjoyed errors with no noticeable damage,
但我必须承认，你是我见过的最不像书呆子的人
But, I must admit, you're the farthest thing from a bookworm I've ever seen.
弗林特是我的老师，你们是我见过的仅有的其他人
Flint is my teacher. You are the only other men I've ever seen.
是全世界人的不幸，是我们的荣幸
The misfortune of men everywhere and our privilege.
如果你陪我的机器人去实验室，医生
If you will accompany my robot to the laboratory, doctor,
你可以放心，瑞他啉正在处理中
you can rest assured that the ryetalyn is being processed.
谢谢，先生
Thank you, sir.
你们喜欢什么，先生们？象棋、台球、谈话？
Your pleasure, gentlemen? Chess, billiards, conversation?
为什么不一起呢？
Why not all three?
你教过她吗？
Did you teach her that?
我们经常玩
We play often.
我能露一手吗，舰长？
May I show you, Captain?
你提到了野蛮，弗林特先生
You said something about savagery, Mr. Flint.
你上次访问地球是什么时候？
When was the last time you visited earth?
[弗林特] 你要告诉我它不再残酷了
[Flint] You would tell me it is no longer cruel.
但它就是残酷的，舰长
But it is, Captain.
看看你的星舰，满是武器
Look at your starship, bristling with weapons.
它的使命是殖民、剥削、摧毁，如有必要
Its mission, to colonize, exploit, destroy, if necessary
推进联邦事业
to advance Federation causes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们的任务是和平的，我们的武器是防御性的
Our missions are peaceful, our weapons defensive.
如果我们是野蛮人，我们就不会请求要瑞他啉
If we were barbarians, we would not have asked for ryetalyn.
实际上，你的问候，而不是我们的问候，缺乏某种仁慈
Indeed, your greeting, not ours, lacked a certain benevolence.
压力的结果不是你关心的
The result of pressures which are not your concern.
是的，每个人都承受着这些无处不在的压力，促使他做出你所谓的野蛮行为
Yes. Well, those pressures are everywhere in everyone, urging him to what you call savagery.
个人的地狱，内心的需求和奥秘，本能的野兽
The private hells, the inner needs and mysteries, the beast of instinct.
作为人类，就是这样的
As human beings, that is the way it is.
作为人类代表着复杂
To be human is to be complex.
你无法避免来自内部和外部的一丁点缺陷
You can't avoid a little ugliness from within and from without.
[钢琴演奏]
[Piano Plays]
史波克先生，你为什么不演奏华尔兹？
Why don't you play the waltz, Mr. Spock?
作为人类也意味着寻求快乐、欢笑、跳舞
To be human is also to seek pleasure, to laugh, to dance.
蕾娜是一位有造诣的舞者
Rayna is a most accomplished dancer.
我能有这个荣幸吗？
May I have the pleasure?
有什么事吗？
Is something wrong?
是的，有问题，瑞他啉有问题
Yes, there's something wrong. The ryetalyn is no good.
它含有釴，接近千分之一
It contains irillium, nearly one part per thousand.
釴会使抗毒素变得惰性和无用
Irillium will render the antitoxin inert and useless.
真不幸之前没有发现
Most unfortunate that it was not detected.
我会和M-4一起去收集更多的瑞他啉并亲自筛选
I shall go with M-4 to gather more ryetalyn and screen it myself.
欢迎你和我一起，医生
You're welcome to join me, Doctor.
谢谢
Thank you.
时间因素，老骨头？传染病
Time factor, Bones? Epidemic.
接近两个半小时，我想我们有时间能及时赶上
Nearly two and a half hours. I guess we got time to get in under the wire.
[麦考伊] 我从来没有见过比这机器人更快的
[McCoy]I've never seen anything like the speed of that robot.
这将花费我们两倍的时间处理那个东西
It'd take us twice as long to process that stuff.
[柯克] 但是要是我们弄错了怎么办？
[Kirk] But would we have made the error?
吉姆，如果这个星球上所有的瑞他啉都含有釴怎么办？
Jim, what if all the ryetalyn on this planet contains irillium?
和弗林特一起去，盯着整个流程
Go with Flint. Keep an eye on procedures.
像一只鹰
Like a hawk.
舰长，另一个相当非凡的东西
Captain, something else which is rather extraordinary.
我刚刚演奏的这首华尔兹是约翰内斯·勃拉姆斯的
This waltz I just played is by Johannes Brahms.
等会儿，史波克
Later, Spock.
舰长，这是原始手稿
Captain, it is written in manuscript.
勃拉姆斯亲手写的原始手稿，我认出来了
In original manuscript in Brahms' own hand, which I recognize.
完全不为人知，绝对是勃拉姆斯的作品
It is totally unknown, definitely the work of Brahms,
并且不为人知
and yet unknown.
我要去实验室
I think I will go to the laboratory.
也许有方法可以逆转釴的作用，并保住现有的抗毒素
There may be a way of reversing the irillium's effect and saving the existing antitoxin.
待在这，让我知道弗林特和麦考伊什么时候回来
Stay here. Let me know when Flint and McCoy return.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5843.75
[Kirk] Captain's log, stardate 5843.75.
我是否错误听信了弗林特的话？
Have I committed a grave error in accepting Flint's word
他说会把解药交给我们
that he would deliver the antidote to us?
我所浪费的宝贵时间可能会给企业号及其船员带来灾难
The precious time I have let past may result in disaster for the Enterprise and her crew.
你离开了我们，房间变得孤独
You left us. The room became lonely.
是一种口渴
It is a thirst.
一朵花在沙漠中死去
A flower dying in the desert.
什么？
What?
里面有什么？
What's in there?
我不知道
I do not know.
弗林特告诉我永远别进去
Flint told me never to enter.
他不拒绝我别的事情
He denies me nothing else.
那你为什么在这里？
Then why are you here?
我不知道
I do not know.
我烦恼的时候来这里
I come here when I am troubled.
找寻自我的时候
When I would search myself.
你现在烦恼吗？
Are you troubled now?
是的
Yes.
因为什么？
By what?
你和弗林特一起住这里开心吗？
Are you happy here with Flint?
他是银河系中最伟大、最善良、最聪明的人
He is the greatest, kindest, wisest man in the galaxy.
那你为什么害怕？
Then why are you afraid?
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
终止命令
Stop command.
终止
Stop.
谢谢你，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
幸好机器人没有发现我的存在
Fortunately, the robot did not detect my presence
并解除我的相位枪
and deactivate my phaser.
M-4被设计用来保护这个家庭及其成员
M-4 was programmed to defend this household and its members.
毫无疑问，我应该修改它的指令
No doubt I should have altered its instructions
来允许你采取未经授权但可预测的行动
to allow for unauthorized but predictable actions on your part.
它以为你在攻击蕾娜
It thought you were attacking Rayna.
一个误解
A misinterpretation.
如果它现在就在身边，它会纠正…
If it were around right now, it would correct...
非常有用不可或缺的设备，真的，我还做了一个
Too useful a device to be without, really. I created another.
它现在将前往实验室并与麦考伊医生会合
It will now go to the laboratory and join Dr. McCoy.
真有意思
Fascinating.
幸亏你没有攻击我，舰长
Be thankful that you did not attack me, Captain.
否则我大概已经接受了战斗，我的体力是你的两倍
I might have accepted battle and I have twice your physical strength.
用你自己的话来说，这将是一次“有趣的权力测试”
In your own words, it would be an "interesting test of power."
他真是孩子气啊，蕾娜
How childish he is, Rayna.
你会称他为勇敢还是傻瓜？
Would you call him brave or a fool?
我很高兴他没有死
I'm glad he did not die.
当然，死亡，在不必要的时候，是一件悲惨的事情
Of course. Death, when unnecessary, is a tragic thing.
麦考伊医生和新的瑞他啉在实验室里
[Flint] Dr. McCoy's in the laboratory with the new ryetalyn.
他对它的质量很满意
He's satisfied with its quality.
我可以建议你在这里耐心、安全地等待吗？
May I suggest that you wait here patiently, safely?
你已经见识过了，我的防御系统自动运行
You have seen that my defense systems operate automatically
并不总是按照我的意愿
and not always in accordance with my wishes.
来吧，蕾娜
Come, Rayna.
蕾娜
Rayna.
来
Come.
我不喜欢他命令她的方式
I don't like the way he orders her around.
既然我们依靠弗林特先生来提供瑞他啉，舰长
Since we are dependent on Mr. Flint for the ryetalyn, Captain,
我恭敬地建议你少关注些这位小姐
may I respectfully suggest that you pay less attention to the young lady
如果你再次遇到她的话
if you should encounter her again.
我们东道主的兴趣似乎不仅限于艺术和科学
Our host's interests do not appear to be confined to art and science.
他爱她？
He loves her?
表现得很明显
Strongly indicated.
妒忌
Jealousy.
是的，这可以解释这次袭击
Yes, that would explain the attack,
但他似乎希望我们在一起
but he seemed to want us together.
台球比赛
The billiard game.
他建议我们跳舞
He suggested we dance.
据我所知，它似乎确实违背了男性的逻辑
It does appear to defy the male logic, as I understand it.
柯克呼叫企业号，斯科特先生
Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott.
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain
关于瑞吉利热的报告
Report on the Rigelian fever.
船上几乎每个人都感染了，舰长
Nearly everybody aboard has got it, Captain.
我们正在组建一个骨干团队，并等待瑞他啉
We're working a skeleton crew and waiting for the ryetalyn.
[柯克] 再等一会儿，斯科提
[Kirk] Just a little while longer, Scotty.
计算机检索报告
Report on the computer search.
没有关于弗林特先生的报道
There's no report on Mr. Flint.
他似乎没有任何过去
He doesn't seem to have any past.
这颗星球是30年前被布拉克先生买下的
The planet was purchased 30 years ago by a Mr. Brack,
一个富有的金融家和隐士
a wealthy financier and recluse.
用电脑检查蕾娜·卡佩克
Run a computer check on Rayna Kapec.
身份，父母去世后的合法监护人
Status, legal ward after the death of her parents.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
通话完毕，斯科特先生
Kirk out, Mr. Scott.
我们还有一个更大的谜团，舰长
We have still a greater mystery, Captain.
我能用三录仪对弗林特先生进行扫描
I was able to run a tricorder scan on Mr. Flint.
他是人类，但某些生物物理特性
He is human, but there are certain biophysical peculiarities,
一些身体机能读数不成比例
some body-function readings are disproportionate.
比如，显示了极端年龄，大约为6,000年
For one thing, extreme age is indicated, on the order of 6,000 years.
史波克先生，你能确认一下吗？
Can you confirm that, Mr. Spock?
我将通过麦考伊医生的医疗计算机对读数进行编程
I shall program the readings through Dr. McCoy's medical computer
当我们回到船上时
when we return to the ship.
时间因素？
Time factor?
我们必须在两小时十八分钟内开始注射瑞他啉
We must commence ryetalyn injections within two hours and 18 minutes,
否则这场流行病对我们所有人来说都是致命的
or the epidemic will prove fatal to us all.
现在是什么在进行处理？
What's keeping the processing this time?
耽搁可能是故意的
The delay may be deliberate.
好像他出于某种原因把我们留在这里
As though he was keeping us here for some reason.
真有趣，我们的主人似乎希望我们逗留
Most interesting. Our host appears to wish us to linger,
然而他很担心
yet he is apprehensive.
我们很可能被监视了
It is logical to assume that we are being monitored
而且他知道我们的一举一动
and that he is aware of our every move.
你派机器人去杀了他
You sent the robot to kill him.
它是来保护你的
It came to protect you.
我的思维并没有召唤它，我不害怕
My mind could not have summoned it. I was not frightened.
那么它是有缺陷的，我会自己摧毁它
It was defective, then. I would have destroyed it myself.
我骗过你吗？
Have I lied to you?
从没
Never.
相信我说的话，我不希望柯克舰长死
Believe what I say. I would not want Captain Kirk dead.
你有什么感觉？
What did you feel?
你会让他们拿到瑞他啉吗？
You'll let them have the ryetalyn?
是的
Yes.
如果你愿意，去找他们，和他们告别
Go to them if you wish. Say your farewells.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
我是斯科特先生，长官
Mr. Scott, sir.
联邦司法库中没有蕾娜·卡佩克的记录
There's no record of a Rayna Kapec in Federation legal banks.
没有监护人？
No ward of custody?
任何电脑库中都没有背景资料
No background in any computer banks.
和弗林特一样
Like Flint.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
"和弗林特一样"
"Like Flint."
没有过去的人
People without a past.
他对她有什么影响？
What hold does he have over her?
舰长，我想说眼下我们最关心的是瑞他啉
Captain, I would suggest our immediate concern is the ryetalyn.
让我们找到麦考伊
Let's find McCoy.
舰长
Captain.
我和你在实验室碰头
I'll meet you in the lab.
我是来告别的
I've come to say goodbye.
我不想说再见
I don't want to say goodbye.
最后一次温柔的邂逅，柯克舰长，结束你的作用
A last tender encounter, Captain Kirk, to end your usefulness.
我告诉你，史波克，我在等机器人完成处理
I tell you, Spock, I was waiting for the robot to finish the processing
接着我知道的就是它就不见了，瑞他啉也是
and the next thing I knew it was gone and so was the ryetalyn.
有趣
Interesting.
显然，弗林特先生还没有准备好让我们离开
Obviously, Mr. Flint is not yet ready for us to depart.
嗯，我想最好告诉吉姆
Well, I think we'd better tell Jim.
舰长要我们在这里等
The captain wanted us to wait here.
跟我走
Come with me.
…我给你幸福
...I offer you happiness.
我了解这里的安保措施
I've known security here.
童年必须结束
Childhood must end.
你爱我，而不是弗林特
You love me, not Flint.
弗林特撒谎，瑞他啉不在这里
Flint lied. The ryetalyn isn't here.
收到三录仪读数，舰长
Picking up tricorder readings, Captain.
显然，瑞他啉在这扇门后面
Apparently, the ryetalyn is behind this door.
为什么弗林特要对我们耍花招？
Why is Flint playing tricks on us?
显然，如果可以的话，我们应该进去拿它
Apparently, we're supposed to go in and get it if we can.
让我们不要让象棋大师失望
Let's not disappoint the chess master.
相位枪全功率
Phasers on full.
舰长，我去拿瑞他啉
Captain, I shall get the ryetalyn.
为什么是你？
Why you?
里面可能有危险
There may be dangers within.
让我们去看看
Let's find out.
让我一个人去吧，舰长
Let me go alone, Captain.
为什么？说重点，史波克，如果有的话
Why? Get to the point, Spock, if there is one.
我们一起去
We'll all go.
瑞他啉
The ryetalyn.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5843.8
[Kirk] Captain's log, stardate 5843.8.
我们已经有了用于在企业号上抗击疫情的瑞他啉
We have the ryetalyn ready to combat the epidemic aboard the Enterprise.
但我们也发现了捐助者的秘密
But we have also discovered our benefactor's secret.
他创造了完美的女人
He has created the perfect woman.
她唯一的缺点是她不是人类
Her only flaw she's not human.
肉体上是人，但不是人
Physically human, but not human.
这些是蕾娜的早期版本，吉姆
These are earlier versions of Rayna, Jim.
她是机器人
She's an android.
我亲手在这里创造的
Created here by my hand.
几个世纪的孤独将在这里结束
Here the centuries of loneliness were to end.
弗林特先生，你收藏的列奥纳多·达·芬奇杰作
Your collection of Leonardo da Vinci masterpieces, Mr. Flint,
似乎是最近画的
appear to have been recently painted
在当代帆布上用当代材料
on contemporary canvas with contemporary materials.
你钢琴上的约翰内斯·勃拉姆斯的华尔兹
And on your piano, the waltz by Johannes Brahms,
一部未知的作品，以现代墨水书写的手稿
an unknown work, in manuscript, written in modern ink.
然而绝对真实，就像你的画一样
Yet absolutely authentic, as are your paintings.
我就是勃拉姆斯
I am Brahms.
也是达芬奇？
And da Vinci?
是的
Yes.
你还有多少个别的名字？
How many other names shall we call you?
所罗门、亚历山大、拉撒路、玛士撒拉、梅林、艾布拉姆森
Solomon, Alexander, Lazarus, Methuselah, Merlin, Abramson.
100个你不知道的其他名字
100 other names you do not know.
你出生在？
You were born?
地球上那个后来被称为美索不达米亚的地区
In that region of Earth later called Mesopotamia,
公元前3834年
in the year 3834 BC,
正如千年来所认为的那样
as the millennia are reckoned.
我是阿卡林
I was Akharin.
一个士兵，一个恶霸和一个傻瓜
A soldier, a bully and a fool.
我在战斗中倒下，刺穿了心脏，并没有死去
I fell in battle, pierced to the heart, and did not die.
即时组织再生
Instant tissue regeneration
再加上一些完美的生物再生形式
coupled with some perfect form of biological renewal.
你知道了你是不死的…
You learned that you're immortal...
并隐瞒了它
And to conceal it.
过着生活的一部分
To live some portion of a life.
在我的天性被怀疑之前假装变老然后继续前进
To pretend to age and then move on before my nature was suspected.
你的财富和智力是几个世纪以来积累的产物
Your wealth and your intellect are the product of centuries of acquisition.
你认识历史上最伟大的杰出人物
You knew the greatest minds in history.
伽利略、苏格拉底、摩西
Galileo, Socrates, Moses.
我已经结了100次婚了，舰长
I have married 100 times, Captain.
选择过，爱过，珍视过
Selected, loved, cherished,
抚摸过光滑的肌肤
caressed a smoothness,
闻到过短暂的芬芳
inhaled a brief fragrance.
然后是衰老，死亡，尘土的味道，你明白吗？
Then age, death, the taste of dust. Do you understand?
你想要一个完美的、最好的女人
You wanted a perfect, ultimate woman,
像你自己一样才华横溢，不朽
as brilliant, as immortal, as yourself.
你永远的伴侣
Your mate for all time.
我用心设计，对她的爱无法更甚
Designed by my heart. I could not love her more.
史波克，你早就知道了？
Spock, you knew?
我希望我错了
I'd hoped I was wrong.
你不能爱一个机器人，舰长，我爱她
You cannot love an android, Captain. I love her.
她是我的杰作，我的所有，她就是我想要的
She is my handiwork, my property. She is what I desire.
你带我来就是让我知道这事？
You brought me here to learn this?
她知道吗？
Does she know?
她永远不会知道
She will never know.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你会留下来
You will stay.
为什么？
Why?
我们已经发现了他的身份，舰长
We have discovered what he is, Captain.
如果你离开，好奇的人就会接踵而至
If you leave, the curious would follow.
愚蠢的人、爱管闲事的人、官员、探索者
The foolish, the meddlers, the officials, the seekers.
我的隐私是我自己的
My privacy was my own.
对它的侵犯算在你的头上
Its invasion be on your head.
我们可以保持沉默
We can remain silent.
干涉的灾难，我知道的，我不会冒险的
The disaster of intervention, I've known it. I will not risk it.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
撤离该区域，通知星际舰队司令部
Clear out of the area. Inform Starfleet Command.
企业号？斯科提？
Enterprise? Scotty?
他们无法回答，舰长
They cannot answer, Captain.
我的船员
My crew.
权力测试
The test of power.
你没有机会
You had no chance.
是时候加入你的船员了
It is time for you to join your crew.
你要消灭400条生命？为什么？
You'd wipe out 400 lives? Why?
我见证过1000亿次的死亡，我比任何人都了解它
I have seen 100 billion fall. I know death better than any man.
我已经把敌人扔到他的手里了
I have tossed enemies into his grasp.
我懂得怜悯，你的船员没有死，而是被暂停了
And I know mercy. Your crew is not dead, but suspended.
比死亡还糟糕，恢复它们，恢复我的船
Worse than dead. Restore them. Restore my ship.
早晚，1000年，2000年，你会知道未来的，柯克舰长
In time. 1,000, 2,000 years. You will know the future, Captain Kirk.
你就是这样的人
You have been such men.
你知道并创造了这样的美好
You've known and created such beauty.
在你漫长的一生中，你见证了你的种族从野蛮进化而来
You've watched your race evolve from barbarism throughout your enormous life,
然而你会这样对我们吗？
and yet now you would do this to us?
我过去的美好，我现在的烦恼
The flowers of my past. I hold the nettles of the present.
我现在是弗林特，有我的需要
I am Flint now, with my needs.
什么需要
What needs?
今晚我看到了一些奇妙的东西，我等待，我为之努力的东西
Tonight I've seen something wondrous, something I've waited for, labored for.
不能有东西危及它
Nothing must endanger it.
蕾娜的情绪终于有了波动
At last Rayna's emotions have stirred.
现在这些情绪将在我保留的孤寂之地中投向我
Now they will turn to me in this solitude which I preserve.
不
No.
蕾娜
Rayna.
你不能这么对他们
You must not do this to them.
我一定要
I must.
我们走了之后，你会对他有什么感觉？
What will you feel for him after we are gone?
弗林特先生，所有情感都在起作用
All emotions are in play, Mr. Flint.
你伤害我们，她恨你
You harm us, she hates you.
把我的船还给我，我们不会泄露你的秘密
Give me back my ship. Your secret is safe with us.
这就是为什么你推迟了瑞他啉的处理
That's why you delayed the processing of the ryetalyn.
你意识到发生了什么
You realized what was happening.
你让我们在一起，蕾娜和我
You kept us together, Rayna and me.
因为你知道我可以让她的情感活跃起来
Because you knew I could bring her emotions alive.
而现在你要夺走？
Now you're just going to take over?
当她来找我时，我会拿走属于我的东西
I shall take what is mine, when she comes to me.
我们是一对，舰长，一样的，不朽的
We are mated, Captain. Alike, immortal.
你必须忘记你在这件事上的感觉，这对你来说是完全不可能的
You must forget your feelings in this matter, which is quite impossible for you.
不可能！
Impossible!
不可能
Impossible.
从一开始，你就利用了我
From the beginning, you used me.
我不能爱她
I can't love her.
但我确实爱她
But I do love her.
她也爱我
And she loves me.
不！
No!
舰长，你的原始冲动不会改变状况
Captain, your primitive impulses will not alter the circumstances.
别插手，我们为一个女人而战
Stay out of this. We're fighting over a woman.
不，你们不是，因为她不是
No, you're not, for she is not.
我不能成为这件事的起因
I cannot be the cause of this.
我不会成为这件事的起因
I will not be the cause of this.
请停下
Please stop.
停！
Stop!
我选择我想去的地方
I choose where I want to go.
我想做的事
What I want to do.
我来选择
I choose.
蕾娜！
Rayna!
不
No,
不要命令我
do not order me.
没有人可以命令我
No one can order me.
她是人类
She's human.
哪怕只有最后一个血细胞，她都是人类
Down to the last blood cell, she's human.
哪怕只剩最后的想法，希望，抱负，情感，她都是人
Down to the last thought, hope, aspiration, emotion, she's human.
人类精神是自由的，你没有所有权
The human spirit is free. You have no power of ownership.
她可以随心所欲
She's free to do as she wishes.
先生们，我劝你们停下来
Gentlemen, I urge you to stop.
有危险
There is a danger.
没有人能打败我
No man beats me.
我不想打败你
I don't want to beat you.
这不是对权力测试
This is no test of power.
蕾娜属于她自己
Rayna belongs to herself.
她要求拥有人类选择的权利
And she claims the human right of choice,
成为她想成为的
to be as she wills.
做她想做的，想她所想的！
To do as she wills, to think as she wills!
这就是我一直努力的东西
That's what I've worked for.
蕾娜跟我走
Rayna come with me.
留下
Stay.
我本来不是人类
I was not human.
现在我爱恋
Now I love.
我爱恋
I love.
你不能死
You can't die.
发生了什么？
What happened?
她爱你，舰长
She loved you, Captain.
你也是，弗林特先生，作为导师，甚至作为父亲
And you, too, Mr. Flint, as a mentor, even as a father.
她没有足够的时间适应这可怕的力量
There was not enough time for her to adjust to the awful power
以及她新发现的情感的矛盾
and contradictions of her new-found emotions.
她不忍伤害你们任何一个
She could not bear to hurt either of you.
爱的快乐使她成为人，爱的痛苦摧毁了她
The joys of love made her human and the agonies of love destroyed her.
史波克
Spock.
疫情减轻，不再构成威胁了
The epidemic is reduced and no longer a threat.
企业号在航线513，标记7，按照你的命令
The Enterprise is on course 513, mark 7, as you ordered.
一个很老很孤独的人
A very old and lonely man.
还有一个年轻而孤独的人
And a young and lonely man.
我们演了一出很拙劣的戏码，是不是？
We put on a pretty poor show, didn't we?
要是我能忘记就好了
If only I could forget.
吉姆
Jim.
谢天谢地，终于睡觉了
Thank heaven, sleeping at last.
你的报告，医生
Your report, Doctor.
哦，弗林特先生的三录仪读数终于相关了
Oh, those, uh, tricorder readings on Mr. Flint are finally correlated.
他快死了
He's dying.
你看，弗林特在带着塑造他的复杂场
You see, Flint, in leaving Earth, with all of its complex fields
离开地球时，牺牲了不朽
within which he was formed, sacrificed immortality.
他将过完正常的生活，然后死去
He'll live the rest of a normal life and die.
那一天，我会哀悼
On that day, I shall mourn.
他知道吗？
Does he know?
是的，我告诉他了，他打算把余生
Yes, I told him myself. He intends to devote the remainder of his years
和他的伟大能力奉献给人类健康的改善
and great abilities to the improvement of the human condition.
谁知道他会想出什么？
And who knows what he might come up with.
的确
Indeed.
好吧，我想这就是全部，我可以稍后告诉吉姆，或者你来说
Well, I guess that's all. I can tell Jim later, or you can.
考虑到对手的长寿，真是一个永恒的三角恋
Considering his opponent's longevity, truly an eternal triangle.
你不会明白的，对吧史波克？
You wouldn't understand that, would you Spock?
你看，我为你比为他感到更难过
You see, I feel sorrier for you than I do for him,
因为你永远不会知道爱情能驱使一个人做什么
because you'll never know the things that love can drive a man to.
狂喜，痛苦
The ecstasies, the miseries,
破坏规则
the broken rules,
孤注一掷的冒险
the desperate chances,
光荣的失败和光荣的胜利
the glorious failures and the glorious victories.
这些东西你永远不会知道
All of these things you'll never know
只是因为"爱"这个词没有写进你的字典里
simply because the word "love" isn't written into your book.
晚安，史波克
Good night, Spock.
晚安，医生
Good night, Doctor.
我真希望他能忘记她
I do wish he could forget her.
忘记
Forget.